Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
Sheet music collection on medical themes
1762-1989
1890-1940
Pam Coll 5
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
18
Sheet music on medical themes including songs and piano compositions about medical providers, ailments, remedies, health for children, and advertisements for medical products. Much of the music was performed in music halls or as part of musicals, or later, performed on radio, television, and on records.
Helfand, William H.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by William H. Helfand, 2013.
Biographical / Historical
These materials were collected by William H. Helfand, a former pharmaceutical company executive, a historian of medicine, and a longtime collector of materials, especially prints and ephemera, related to the history of medicine.
Scope and Contents
Series 1 consists of sheet music in English in alphabetical order by title. Most items were published in London or in various cities in the United States, especially New York. The songs include alma maters and other music for the medical professions, humorous songs about incompetent healers and hawkers of remedies, many sentimental songs about Red Cross nurses treating wounded soldiers in World War I, songs for children to sing, songs about particular maladies (rheumatism) or remedies (cod liver oil), and popular songs that refer to physicians, chiropractors, dentists, nurses, and drug stores. Many songs from the 19th and early twentieth century were featured in music halls or as part of musicals. Portraits of performers are often featured on the cover of the sheet music. Some songs are radio theme songs. For the more recent period, there are recorded songs like Eric Clapton singing "Cocaine" or Loretta Lynn singing "The Pill," as well as theme songs from early TV shows on doctors and hospitals.
Series 2 consists of sheet music in French, arranged by size and then alphabetically. Most items were published in Paris, and most are from the 19th century or early 20th century. The lithographic cover illustrations are often by well-known printmakers. Many of the songs are part of comic scenes that contain both music and spoken words. Others are comic monologues.
Series 3 consists of a few songs in German and Dutch and several tangos from Buenos Aires, Argentina, notable for their colored cover illustrations of medical scenes and the dedication of the music to physicians.
In all these series, a number of items are incomplete and represented by an illustrated cover only, or a cover and a single page of music on the reverse.
Series 4 includes sheet music that advertises a product--usually a patent medicine--or a practitioner. Sometimes the songs or musical pieces are popular and unrelated to medicine, while other times, the words of the song directly praise the product.
Series 5 is a very large collection of sheet music published by Emerson Drug Company, Baltimore, to advertise Bromo Seltzer. These date from about 1890 to 1910. The songs themselves are popular and sentimental.
Series 6, "Miscellaneous," includes sheet music advertising St. Jacob's Oil and Beecham's Pills; song books of several musicals on doctors; books of songs published by medical schools; and songs and songbooks by publishers who took patent medicine advertisements to lower the cost of selling the music.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: 1. Individual songs in English by title. 2. Individual songs in French by title, subdivided into large and small format. 3. Individual songs in other languages; Argentine tangos. 4. Music advertising a product or a practitioner. 5. Bromo-Seltzer sheet music. 6. Miscellaneous.
Advertising -- Health products -- United States; Children's songs; Chiropractors; Dentists; Drugstores; Gout; Headache; Humorous songs -- United States; Hydrotherapy; Lovesickness; Measles; Medicine -- Humor; Mental illness; Microorganisms; Military hospitals -- Great Britain; Military hospitals -- United States; Military nursing -- France; Military nursing -- Great Britain; Military nursing -- United States; Mumps; Music-halls; Nurses; Patent medicines -- Great Britain; Patent medicines -- United States; Pharmacists; Physicians -- France; Physicians -- Great Britain; Physicians -- Humor; Physicians -- United States; Popular music; Quacks and quackery; Rheumatism; Syphilis; Tangos -- Argentina; World War, 1914-1918 -- Medical care -- Great Britain; World War, 1914-1918 -- Medical care -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Medical care -- United States; Advertisements -- American; Advertisements -- British; Children's songs; Minstrel songs; Sheet music; Songs; American National Red Cross. Nursing Service; Beecham's Pills (Firm); Charles A. Vogeler Company; Emerson Drug Co; Helfand, William H., 1926- -- Ownership
- Individual songs in English by title, 1.
  Physicians -- France -- 20th century
  - 98.6 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Words by Tony Powers, music by George Fischoff. New York: Screen Gems - Columbia Music, Inc., c. 1966. "Recorded by Keith on Mercury Records."
  - Adverts of Modern Medicine
  - All for the Bart's: Fox Trot Song
    Words by Jerome Chester, music by Herbert Oliver. London: J. H. Larway, n.d. "Proceeds of the sales of this fox-trot go to the funds of St. Bartholomew's Hospital."
  - All Isn't Bliss that Blisters: Song for Boys
    Words by Marie Iris, music by Thos. B. Weaver. Dayton, Ohio: Paine Publishing Co., c. 1922.
  - All Things that Heal
    Words by Samuel Menashe, music by John Brodbin Kennedy. Oceanside, N.Y.: Boosey and Hawkes, c. 1966.
  - Allergies
    Words and music by Paul Simon. New York: Warner Bros. Publications, c. 1981, 1983.
  - Alma Mater of Lima Memorial Hospital School of Nursing
    Words by Doris Goswell, music by "Ruth Boaz '46." No information on publication.
  - A.M.A. March (American Medical Association)
    Piano solo by Joseph Gallicchio and Don Marcotte. New York: Remick Music Corporation, c. 1943.
  - Ammoniated Tincture of Quinine: Comedy Song Fox Trot
    Words by R. Hargreaves and Stanley Damerell, music by Tolchard Evans. London: Cecil Lennox Ltd., c. 1928
  - The Angel God Sent From Heaven
    Words by Paul A. Smith and Robert Levenson, music by Sgt. Frank L. Ventre. Boston: Jack Mendelsohn Music Co., c. 1918. On Red Cross nurses.
  - The Angel of No Man's Land
    Words by H. MacDonald Barr, music by Grant Colfax Tullar. New York: Tullar-Meredith Co., c. 1918. On Red Cross nurses.
  - Angels of Mercy
    By Irving Berlin. New York: American National Red Cross, c. 1941. "Written expressly for and dedicated to American Red Cross."
  - Angels of the Cross of Red: A Waltz Song
    By John D. McDonald. New York: John D. McDonald, c. 1918. "To the brave and unselfish women of America this song is dedicated."
  - Anybody Ill? (I'm Doctor Quack): The Popular Humorous Song
    Music by Alfred Lee, sung by Alf. Walker. London: C. Sheard, n.d.
  - The Apothecaries March
    Composed by Chas. J. Grass. New York: C. H. Ditson & Co, c. 1868.
  - Are We Almost There?: A Touching Ballad
    By Florence Vane. Boston: Oliver Ditson, c. 1845. About a young woman who visits the South for her health, but feels worse, and leaves for home. On the way she kept asking "Are we there yet?" and died just before reaching home. The song was written by a friend who was with her on the journey.
  - At the Foot of the Cross (The Invalid's Dream)
    Words by Mary Ruth Meyer, music by Everett J. Evans. Brunswick, Georgia: Mary Ruth Meyer Music Co., c. 1917
  - Aunt Jemima's Plaster
    By M.A.I., written for and sung by Samuel S. Sanford. Philadelphia: Winner & Shuster, c. 1855. Aunt Jemima made a living selling plasters.
  - Auntie Maggie's Remedy
    By George Formby and Eddie Latta, additional words by Peter Buchanan. London: Lawrence Wright Music Co., Ltd, c. 1966. "Featured by Alan Randall."
  - Auto-Suggestion: Humorous Patter Song
    "Written, composed and sung by Herbert Mundin and Lawrence Jackson." London: Reynolds & Co., n.d.
  - The Ballyslaughter Hydro: Humorous Song
    Words and music by Frank Booth. London: Reynolds & Co., ca. 1890. Sung by Nelson Jackson.
  - Before and After Taken
    By Chas. Horowitz. Milwaukee, Wisconsin: Chas. K. Harris, c. 1895. The first verse is about a man who takes a medicine and regrets it. Other verses are political.
  - Betsy Wareing
    Written and arranged by Henry Walker. London: Metzler & Co., n.d. (19th cent). On her rheumatic joints. Sung by "Mr. Howard Paul in his Musical Entertainment Patchwork."
  - "Ben Casey," Theme from
    By David Raskin. Marfran Music Co., c. 1961. Chappell & Co., Inc., New York, sole selling agent.
  - Bill's Asthma
    Written, composed and sung by Reeves Hansford. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1922. "Dedicated to Tom Titt."
  - Biology
    Words by Sid Wayne, music by Sherman Edwards, arranged by Chris Langdon. Copyright 1960 by Empress Music Inc., New York. Published by Frank Music Co., London. Recorded by Sue Raney on Capitol Records.
  - Blue Glass Galop
    Music by Samuel H. Speck. New York: Millet & Co., c. 1877.
  - Blue Star: The "Medic" Theme
    Words by Edward Heyman, music by Victor Young. Victor Young Publications, Inc., c. 1955. Sole selling agent Chappell & Co., Inc, New York. "As recorded by Felicia Sanders on Columbia Records."
  - Brown-Sequard's Elixir
    Words and music by J. Winchell Forbes. Cincinnati: The Newhall & Evans Music Co,, c. 1889.
  - Call Me Up Some Rainy Afternoon
    Words and music by Irving Berlin. New York: Ted Snyder Co., c. 1910. No medical content other than the image of a corner drugstore on the cover
  - Call Me Up Some Rainy Afternoon
    Words and music by Irving Berlin. New York: Ted Snyder Co., c. 1910. Version of the previous item with an image of a different singer.
  - Carbarlick Acid Rag
    By Clarence C. Wiley. Detroit; New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co. Copyright 1904 by Giles Brothers, Quincy, Ill. Copyright transferred 1907 to Jerome H. Remick & Co.
  - Castor Oil
    Words by Thos. Snowden, music by Frank Sitt. New York: John T. Hall, 1914.
  - Charlie Dear, Mother's Taken Awfully Queer
    Written and composed by G. W. Hunt, arranged by W. Sim. Philadelphia: M.D. Swisher, n.d. About a mother-in-law who is a hypochondriac.
  - Chills and Fever Rag (Two-Step)
    By Theron C. Bennett. Cleveland: Sam Fox Pub. Co., c. 1912.
  - Chiro (Kyro) My Miracle Man
    Words by J. Freeman Otto and C.W. Marek, music by Dennis A. Monaco. New York: Chiropractic Scientific Club, 1920.
  - The Chiropractor March
    Composed by W. T. Williams. Lynn, Mass.: W. T. Williams, c. 1914. "Dedicated to Doctors I. A. Wetherell and S. Mendelssohn, D.O.D.C. Chiropractors of Lynn, Mass."
  - Chloroform Blues
    By John W. Felton. Chicago: Felton Music Publishers, 1921.
  - Cocaine
    Words and music by J. J. Cale. Copyright 1975 by Audigram Music, Nashville, Tenn. This arrangement copyright 1980 by Audigram Music. Recorded by Eric Clapton.
  - Cod Liver Oil (A Song of the Sick Room)
    Words by Henry S. Leigh, music by George Grossmith. London: Reynolds & Co., n.d. (turn of 20th cent.) Sung by Grossmith "in his new musical sketch, 'Away For My Health.'"
  - Cod Liver Oil
    Title page only. No music. Sung by Walter Laburnum. London: H. D'Alcorn, n.d. (19th cent.)
  - The Cold Water Cure: Comic Song
    Written by William Ball to the tune of "The Barking Barber." London: Duff & Hodgson, n.d. (19th cent.) Sung by J. Russell.
  - Colds Among the Noses
    Written by Frank W. Green, arranged by T. Westrop. London: C. Sheard, Musical Bouquet Office, n.d. (19th cent.) "The screaming parody on the popular song 'Love Among the Roses.""
  - Complaints, or The Ills of Life
    Written and sung by Edward Terry. London: Hopwood & Crew, n.d. (19th cent.)
  - The Cork Leg
    London: Willey & Co., n.d. Traditional Irish song first published in the early 19th century.
  - The Cork Leg: A Celebrated Comic Song
    New York: Firth & Hall, n.d. Traditional Irish song. Sung by Mr. Latham.
  - The Cork Leg: A Celebrated Comic Song
    Baltimore: G. Willie, Jr., n.d. (19th cent.). Traditional Irish song. Sung by Mr. Burton.
  - Corns for My Country
    Words and music by Leah Cohen, Jean Barry, and Dick Charles. New York: Remick Music Corporation, 1944. "From the Warner Bros. Picture "Hollywood Canteen."
  - The Cough-Drop Shop
    Words and Music by Leslie Sarony. London: Lawrence Wright Music Co., c. 1932. "Comedy one-step song with uke acc." Performed by Jack Hylton and his band.
  - The Crutch Polka
    By Paul Favart. London: Cunningham Boosey & Co., n.d. (early 20th cent.?)
  - Cures by a Curious Curist
    Written by J. F. McArdle. London: Hopwood & Crew, n.d. (19th cent.) Sung by Edward Terry. "Sequel to Edward Terry's celebrated song 'Complaints'." The singer tells of the many patent medicines and other useless cures he has taken for his various ailments.
  - Curious Cures
    Words and music by James Thornton. New York: Jos. W. Sterling & Co., c. 1897. Sung by James Thornton.
  - Dance of the Medicine Man (Box 2)
    Piano solo by John Chagy. Cincinnati: The Wills Music Company, 1960.
  - The Dandy Coloured Coon
    Words by Richard Morton, music by George Le Brun. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1893. Sung by Eugene Stratton. Reference to a doctor's diagnosis of palpitation of the heart in verse 2.
  - Day by Day in Every Way I'm Getting Better Day by Day
    Words by William Jerome, music by Jean Schwartz. New York: Jerome Remick & Co., c. 1923. "The Health Song." "Dedicated to Dr. Emile Coue."
  - The Disorderly Orderly
    Words by Earl Shuman, music by Leon Carr. New York: Paramount Music Corporation, c. 1964. Sung by Sammy Davis, Jr. in the motion picture, "The Disorderly Orderly," starring Jerry Lewis.
  - The Dispensary Doctor
    Cover page only. No music. By Robert Martin. London: Charles Jefferys, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.?). Sung by E. J. Lonnen.
  - Do As the Romans Do
    Words by C. G. Cotes, music by Bennett Scott. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c.1899. Sung by Marie Elsie. About the "Lady Doctor."
  - Do Your Duty Doctor and Cure My Pain
    Words by Irving Berlin, music by Ted Snyder. New York: Ted Snyder Co, c. 1909. Comic images of a black man and woman on the cover.
  - The Doctor
    Words by A. J. Morris, music by Geo. le Brunn. Boston: White-Smith Music Pub. Co., c. 1893. Copyright by G. Sheard & Co.
  - The Doctor
    Words and music by Charlie Midnight, Eddie Schwartz, and Tom Johnston. n.p.: SBK Blackwood Music, Inc., c. 1989. Recorded by The Doobie Brothers on Capitol Records. "Music is the doctor."
  - The Doctor and the Nurse
    No information on creators. New York: Longacre Music Co., c. 1940. Both the doctor and the nurse are women. "Which one should I kiss?" "One of the entertaining 'Melody Tales'." "Special simplified edition."
  - Dr. Baltimore, M.D.
    Words by Schuyler Greene, music by Otto Motzan. New York: T. Harms and Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1915. Sung by Nora Bayes. On homesickness for Baltimore, Maryland.
  - Doctor Bills, or The Little Sick Dolly
    Words and music by Frank L. Bristow. Cincinnati: The Willis Music Company, c. 1903. Copyright by the Geo. B. Jennings Co.
  - Doctor Compus Mentis
    Cover page only, showing an apprentice pouring a remedy in the doctor's shop. Words and music by Tom Haines, Sung by Harry Rickards. London: Henry D'Alcorn & Co., n.d. (turn of 20th cent.)
  - Doctor Cupid
    Words and music by Chas. George. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1921.
  - Dr. David's Private Papers
    Words and music by Vic Millrose and Mark Barkan. New York: Ensign Music Corporation, c. 1966 and 1967. Recorded by Peter Courtney on Viva Records.
  - Doctor De Luxe: The Accent Makes No Difference in the Language of Love
    Play by Otto Hauerbach, music by Kal Hoschna. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1911. Musical play stars Ralph Herz.
  - Doctor De Luxe: For Every Boy Who's Lonely, There's a Girl Who's Lonely Too
    From the musical play, Doctor de Luxe. Play by Otto Hauerbach, music by Karl Hoschna. New York: M. Witmark and Sons, 1911.
  - Doctor De Luxe: No One But You
    Song from the musical Doctor De Luxe. Play by Otto Hauerbach, music by Karl Hoschna. New York: M. Witmark and Sons, c. 1911.
  - Dr. Finlay
    Words by Andy Stewart, music by Neil Grant. Glasgow: Lochside Publishing Co., Ltd., c. 1965.
  - Dr. Gregory Bolus Squill, the Quack Doctor
    Words and music by C.J. Pavitt. London: H. D'Alcorn & Co., n.d. (19th cent.?).
  - Doctor in Love
    By Ken Hare. Filmusic Publishing Co., Ltd., c. 1960. From the film "Doctor in Love."
  - Doctor Kildare, Theme from
    Composed by Jerrald Goldsmith. New York: Metro Goldwyn Mayer Inc, c. 1961, 1962. Licensing rights controlled by Robbins Music Corporation, London. "From the BBC-TV Series "Dr. Kildare," an NBC-TV program produced by MGM." Starring Raymond Massey and Richard Chamberlain.
  - Dr. Kildare, Theme from (Three Stars Will Shine Tonight)
    Words by Hal Winn, music by Jerald Goldsmith and Pete Rugolo. New York: Metro-Goldwyn-Meyer Inc., c. 1961, 1962. From the MGM television series in association with NBC-TV. Recorded by Richard Chamberlain on M-G-M Records.
  - Doctor, Lawyer, Indian Chief
    Words by Paul Francis Webster, music by Hoagy Carmichael. New York: Melrose Music Corp., c. 1945. "As sung by Betty Hutton in the Paramount Picture 'Stork Club'."
  - Dr. Love
    Words and music by Biddu. London: Dick James Music Limited/Subiddu Music Limited, c. 1972. Recorded by Tina Charles. Singer is in love with the doctor.
  - Dr. Munyon
    Words by Vincent Bryan, music by E. Ray Goetz. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c. 1917. Dr. Munyon was a self-promoting seller of remedies. This song pokes fun at him. For songs by Dr. Munyon, see Series 4.
  - Doctor Murphy's Twins
    Words by Edward Atkins, music by Howard S. Vickers. N.p. (U.S.): James E. Hey & Co., c. 1882.
  - Doctor, My Eyes
    By Jackson Browne. New York: Atlantic Music Corp., c. 1970-1972. Recorded by Jackson Browne.
  - Doctor Nevill
    Words and music by Frank Leo. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. (USA) 1897. Sung by Wilkie Bard. The doctor sings the song and boasts of his success.
  - Dr. Osler Offsky Bing
    Words and music by Jack Primrose. Toronto: Harry H. Sparks, 1910. "Featured by Mr. Charles Emery." The doctor sings the song about his success.
  - Doctor Shelley!
    Words and music by Edgar Bateman and Huntley Trevor. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. (USA) 1915. Sung by Harry Champion. Sung by the doctor.
  - Doctor Sniffleswiper (A Child's Best Friend)
    Words and music by Jill Jackson and Sy Miller. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1953 and 1954.
  - Doctor Tom
    Words and music by Bill Hill and Rick St. Jean. Summerlea Music Limited, c. 1970. U.S. rights controlled by Felsted Music Corporation, New York. Recorded by Freedom of Choice on Wand Records. "Doctor Tom, put me on."
  - A Doctor's Lament
    Words and music by Louis J. Decina, M.D. Philadelphia: Chase-Santora Studios, c. 1947. Sung by the doctor.
  - Doctor's Orders
    Words and music by Roger Cook and Geoff Stephens. London: Cookaway Music, Ltd., c. 1973. Recorded by Sunny on CBS. Only love can cure her pain.
  - Doctor's Orders
    Words and music by Roger Cook, Roger Greenaway, and Geoff Stephens. London: Cookaway Music, Ltd., c. 1973. Recorded by Carol Douglas on Midland International Records. Similar to previous item.
  - Doctor's Orders
    Words and music by Rory Bourke, Bruce Channel, and Kieran Kane. n.p., Old friends Music (BMI), Chappell & Co., and Cross Keys Music Publishing Co., c. 1981. Sold by Columbia Pictures Publications, Miami. Sung by Mel McDaniel.
  - Doctor's Orders
    Words and music by Roger Cook, Roger Greenaway, and Geoff Stephens. London: Cookaway Music Ltd., c. 1973. "Recorded by Carol Douglas on Midland International Records."
  - The Doctor's Polka: A Pleasing and Certain Remedy for Low Spirits
    Composed by A. Pestle. London: Addison & Hollier, n.d. (before 1855).
  - The Doctor's Song (I am the Doctor Paracelsus)
    Words and music by Carl Mischka. Lockport, N.Y.: Simmons, Walter & Lewis, c. 1879. Copyright by Wm. A. Pond & Co., New York. From the opera "Doctor of Alcantara" by Wm. C. Compton. Sung by "Doctor Paracelsus."
  - Don't Forget the Red Cross Nurse
    Words and music by Lew Orth, arranged by Chas. K. Hicks. Boston: Orth & Coleman, c. 1917.
  - Don't Tell Me in the Morning What I Did the Night Before
    Words and music by S.D. Robb. Denver: The Robert Sharp Music Co., c. 1913.
  - The Drug Store Cabaret: Up-to-the-Minute Comic Song
    Words by Ralph Bingham, music by Al Sweet. Chicago: Will Rossiter, c. 1920.
  - Drugstore Scene
    Words and music by Marc Blitzstein. New York: Chappell & Co., c. 1938. "Produced by Mercury Theatre under the direction of Orson Welles." Sung by the proprietor of a drugstore who has a mortgage to pay.
  - The Drugstore Song
    Words and music by Harold Rome. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1946. From the musical review "Call Me Mister," presented by Melvyn Douglas and Herman Levin. Nostalgia for the drugstore on the corner.
  - The Duchess Threw Her Crutches Away
    Words by Fred Fisher, music by Harry Jentes. New York: Fred Fisher Music Co., c. 1936.
  - Eleventh Hour, Theme from the
    Composed by Harry Sukman. Metro-Goldwyn-Meyer, c. 1962. Theme from the MGM TV Series in Association with NBC-TV. The series starred Wendell Corey as a psychiatrist, Dr. Theodore Bassett, and Jack Ging as his associate, Dr. Paul Grantham.
  - L'Elisir d'amore
    Quadrille by Charles D'Albert. London: Chappell, n.d. (19th cent). Cover image is of a quack selling a remedy.
  - Emergency, Theme from
    Melville, N.Y.: Duchess Music Corporation, c. 1972, 1974. From the medical television series, "Emergency," starring Robert Fuller, Julie London, Bobby Troup, Randolph Mantooth, and Kevin Tighe.
  - The Eminent Dr. Fizz
    Words by Frank Pixley, music by Gustav Luders. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1901. "Music Supplement of the New York American and Journal, Sunday, June 8, 1902 - pages 5-8." From the musical, "King Dodo." Sung by the doctor.
  - The Evacuations, or An Emetic for Old England Glorys
    Etched broadside with a political cartoon, including a large syringe, and verses to be sung to the tune of "Derry Down." "Registered according to Act of Parliament by Mary Darley in Little Riders Court Leicesterfields." "From the Rial oak Decemr 1762." According to Stephens, a reference source cited in the Library of Congress record for this broadside: "An etched broadside, comprised in two columns of verse below a design. In the latter, Lord Bute, with an ass's head crowned with a thistle and a peacock's feather, stands on a mountebank's stage and blows bubbles towards a mob of men who follow him..." Dated by Stephens November 3, 1762 or after.
  - Father's Got 'Em
    Words and music by Harry Wincott. London: B. Feldman, n.d. (19th cent.). On mental illness, "Hycumflukus on the brain." Sung by Frank Seeley.
  - Five and Twenty Soldiers and a Nurse (The Boy King's Guard)
    Words by Erell Reaves, music by Sherman Myers. London: Cecil Lennox Ltd, c. 1933.
  - Fever
    Words and music by John Davenport and Eddie Cooley. Cincinnati: Jay & Cee Music Corp., c. 1956. Recorded by Peggy Lee on Capitol Records.
  - The Florence Nightingale Pledge
    Music by Dora Flick Flood. Flushing, N.Y.: D.L. Schroeder, c. 1948.
  - Florence Water Cure Quadrilles
    Composed by C. H. Weber. St. Louis: Balmer & Weber, c. 1854. Dedicated to Dr. Charles Munde who was in charge of the Florence Water Cure Establishment, near Northampton Massachusetts.
  - Frenchy, Come to Yankee Land